Denis Moroz

moroz.denis@gmail.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/dmoroz/ https://github.com/denismoroz http://denismoroz.github.io/fend-p2-online-resume

Summary

Principal software developer and senior software development team manager with more than 12 years of hi-tech industry experience. I am always open to new challenges, easily drill into new technologies and use the best practices to achieve the best result possible.

Skills

Python, C++, Android, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PyCharm, AndroidStudio, Git, Celery, D3D.js, Jira, Ngnix, QT, Django, Flask, JavaScript, RabbitMQ, TDD, Agile, Linux(Ubuntu), Android, Windows.

Professional Experience

Software Developer, Blitzler 2017.05-present, remote consulting

- Designed facebook instant game backend and developed a database schema for MongoDB.
- Build REST API service to access backend functions using Flask.
- Archived reliable codebase support and minimized amount of bugs using of TDD for all backend API.
- Created web system administrator's interface using Flask and JavaScript to mange game data objects and input content.

Software Developer, TryValet 2014.01-2017.05

- Designed mobile application backend and developed a database schema for MongoDB.
- Created REST API service to access backend functions using Flask.

Senior Python Developer, Mobsafety 2013.03-2013.09, remote consulting

- Responsible for Mobile Device Management solution for iOS and Android devices.
- Managed a team of four developers working on backend part of the project, used Agile.

Python Developer, LatamIQ 2012.07 – 2013.02, remote consulting

• Built multiple backend services using MySQL that improved efficiency of economic indexes' analysis.

<u>Django Python Developer, Keeyword.com 2011.09 – 2012.06, remote consulting</u>

- Optimized PostgreSQL database schema to store at least 500k of keywords in one project.
- Reorganized HTTP server api to provide fast access to server data.

Python/C++/C Developer, Visionica 2008.03 –2011.06, remote consulting

- Developed server side components for IP cameras recording system using Python and MySQL.
- Integrated Google ProtoBuffs to client side application written in QT.

C/Python/C++/Game Mods Developer, PlayAll 2007.05 – 2008.03, remote consulting

- Developed several mods to control game flow for Q4, HL family, HL2 family, COD 1, COD2, UT2004.
- Implemented Linux Kernel Module and user mode application on Python to protect server side.

Projects

Behaviour Cloning - part of Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree Family location tracker for Android

Education

2017, Udacity, Self-Driving Car Engineer Nanodegree https://goo.gl/jN8WmL

2015, Udacity, Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree http://goo.gl/hPV8BJ

1998-2003, Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radio-Electronics.

Master of Science in Computer Science, specializing in Informational Security and Artificial Intelligence

Certification

June 2014, M101P MongoDB for Developers